Okay, so let's do now an active power
quiz. Suppose we have a processor whose
voltage can be changed between 0.9 and
1.5 volts in 0.1 volt steps. Its
frequency can be changed between 1.8 GHz
and 3 GHz in 0.2 GHz steps. But there is
a relationship between the voltage and
the frequency you have to use. If we
want to use the lowest frequency
setting, our voltage can be 0.9 volts.
If we want to use the next frequency
setting of 2.0 GHz, then the voltage
needs to be 1.0
volt. For 2.2 GHz, we need to use 1.1
volts and so on. And we can only get the
highest 3 GHz frequency with the highest
voltage of 0.1 volts. So you cannot just
lower the voltage and increase the
frequency. If you increase the
frequency, you also have to increase the
voltage. Of course, you are allowed to
use a 2 GHz frequency setting with any
voltage that is 1.0 volts or above. So
we could for example do 2 GHz and 1.5
volts, although that's of course going
to be less power efficient than using
the lowest voltage available for that
frequency. Let's say also that we have
measured the power consumption at 1 volt
and 2 GHz. this setting here and we have
found that the processor consumes 30
watts of power. The questions for you
are what is the power for the most power
efficient setting among these? Put your
answer here. And what is the power for
the highest performance setting among
these? Put your answer here.